目标航向改变
We have a midcourse deviation.
目标航向036 126里
Target heading 036, 126 miles.
方位062 哈瓦那
Bearing 062, Havana, VOR.
降落在魁基
He's landing at Cray Cay.
联络缉毒局探员
Advise Key West Drug Enforcement.
知道了 长官 空中监视器
Roger, sir. AWACS to Key West.
呼叫缉毒局
Key West Drug Enforcement, please come in.
若动作快点 就能逮捕那杂种
If they hurry, they just might be able to grab the bastard.
你确定 你把戒指带来了？
Now, you're sure you've got the ring?
放轻松 菲力克
Relax, Felix.
你朋友？
Friends of yours?
我缉毒局的搭档
My partners at the DEA.
怎么回事？
What the hell is going on?
桑契斯在巴哈马
Sanchez is in the Bahamas.
你们获得总部批准了吗？
Have you cleared it with Nassau?
批准了
We've got the green light.
走吧！菲力克！
Let's go! Hey, Felix, Felix!
你是否忘了什么？
Haven't you forgotten something?
詹姆斯 向德拉解释好吗？
Oh, James, explain to Della, will you?
门都没有 我跟你一起去
No way. I'm coming with you.
好 纯粹观察而已
Okay, but strictly as an observer.
- 抱歉 鲨鱼 - 为何是我？
- Sorry, Sharkey. - Hey, why me?
你们不能这样对我！
Hey, you guys, you can't do this to me!
我要怎么告诉德拉？！
What will I tell Della?
他向你承诺了什么？他的心？
What did he promise you? His heart?
把他的心给她
Give her his heart.
不
No.
不 法兰斯 他并非有意造成任何伤害
No, Franz. I didn't mean any harm.
没关系的 宝贝
It's all right, baby.
我们全都会犯错
We all make mistakes.
你的任性愈来愈有创意了
Your escapades are getting more creative.
什么也别说
Not a word.
他还是没到
He's still not here.
你能再绕一圈吗？
Can you go around the block again?
那些客人怎么办？
What about the guests?
我告诉过你 这是个错误！
I told you this was a mistake!
詹姆斯 以防万一
James, just in case.
好了
Okay.
我要活捉桑契斯！留在这儿 詹姆斯
I want Sanchez alive! Stay here, James.
- 没有桑契斯 - 可恶！
- No Sanchez. - Damn.
小心！
Watch out!
观察员！
Hey, observer!
你想送命吗？
You're trying to get yourself killed?
我若不能把你带回去参加婚礼 那我才死定了呢
If I don't get you back for the wedding, I'm a dead man for sure!
- 你需要协助吗？- 不 别碰我！
- You need help? - No. Take your hands off me.
走开
Just go away.
桑契斯！
Sanchez!
我们走！
Let's go!
走吧！走吧！
Come on! Come on!
他20分钟就能到古巴领空了
He'll be in Cuban airspace in 20 minutes.
他还没逃掉呢！
He hasn't got away yet.
你在干嘛？
What the hell are you doing?
我们去钓鱼！
Let's go fishing!
向前 向前
Forward. Forward.
慢一点 稳住
Easy. Hold it.
退后
Back up. Back up.
往前
Forward now.
停住
Hold it!
把他吊上来！让他头朝下！
Bring him in. Take the load.
不 请回家吧！我十分抱歉
No, please go home. I'm very…
他们来了！
WOMAN: There he is!
走吧 詹姆斯！
Let's go, James!
我们成功了
We made it!
来吧 詹姆斯！
Come along. James!
- 你的帽子 - 谢谢你
- Your hat. - Thank you.
《007系列之杀人执照》
快点！
On the double!
离门远点！
Get away from the door!
桑契斯面对139桩控告
You're facing 139 felony counts, Sanchez.
加起来共936年
Why, that's 936 years.
即使是你出了名的百万贿赂 这次也帮不了你
Even one of your famous million-dollar bribes can't get you out of this one.
二
Two.
什么？
What?
二百万美金
$2 million, U.S.
给任何能让我自由的人
A standing offer for anyone who springs me.
他妈的
God damn it!
你以为是在落后国家？
You think you're in some banana republic?
那些杂碎钱 在这时候没有用的
All that scumbag money won't do you a bit of good here.
很好
Very good.
但我认为 我快回家了
But I think I'm gonna be home soon, huh?
你这个
Why you…
控制一下你自己！
Get a hold of yourself!
我们在广达可有间 单人囚室等你
We got a nice private cell waiting for your ass at Quantico,
我保证你一定会住进去
and I'm going to personally see you get there.
我十分抱歉
I'm terribly sorry!
那是种传统 新娘总是吻男傧相
That's a custom. You see, the bride always gets to kiss her best man.
我以为是男傧相吻新娘才对
I thought it was the other way around.
詹姆斯 你不介意吧？
Oh, James, would you mind?
菲力克还在书房 我们必须切这个蛋糕了
Felix is still in the study, and we've got to cut this cake.
我会为手上拿刀的女人 做任何事的
I'll do anything for a woman with a knife.
谢谢 你们能帮我一下吗？
Thank you. Yes, could you help me here?
- 抱歉 - 不 不 我们结束了
- I'm sorry. - No, no. Come in. We're finished.
潘 见过詹姆斯
Pam, meet James.
再见 菲力克
Goodbye, Felix.
纯粹公事 我的朋友
Strictly business, my friend.
把那东西关掉 菲力克
Switch that thing off, Felix.
你知道你有一屋子的客人在等
You know you have a house full of guests waiting.
让我把这个弄完 请坐
Just let me save this. Take a seat.
我那部门要昨天完整的报告
The department wants a full report, yesterday.
我们今天是运气好
We really hit it lucky today.
桑契斯多年没有离开他的老巢了
Sanchez hasn't been out of his home base for years.
你不能引渡吗？
Well, couldn't you extradite him?
门都没有
Not a chance.
他杀人 威胁 收买
He's killed, intimidated or bribed.
由这里到智利半数政府官员
half the government officials from here to Chile.
在那只有一种法律 桑契斯之法
There's only one law down there, Sanchez's law.
你不是追随就是死
Lead or silver.
艾德！
Ed.
菲尔 恭喜你 老友
Double congratulations, old buddy.
你慢慢渡蜜月 一切都会很好的
You take your time on the honeymoon. Everything's okay.
你一定是邦德了 大老远跑来助一臂之力
You must be Bond, the guy who came along for the ride.
艾德基佛
Ed Killifer.
我们今天下午送桑契斯去广达可
We're taking Sanchez to Quantico this afternoon.
留下来和我们喝一杯
Hey, stay and have a drink with us.
不行 我得赶回去
Can't. Got to get back.
只是顺道来吻新娘的
I just came by to kiss the bride.
菲力克 切蛋糕的时间到了
Felix, it's time to cut the cake.
把德拉的照片给我 快
Hand me the picture of Della. Quick.
她一定准备好要杀我了
She must be ready to kill me.
我亲手绑的
I tied them myself.
- 这些是什么？- 假钓鱼饵
- What are these? - Lures!
这些能使你们忙几天
These'll keep you busy for the next few days.
在我的蜜月上 别想去钓鱼！
I'm not going fishing on my honeymoon!
里面还关了什么人？
How many others are being held in there?
你要带他去哪里？
Where are you taking him, Mr. Killifer?
你为何到巴哈马去？
Now, why did you go to the Bahamas?
桑契斯先生 请看这边 好吗？
Mr. Sanchez, will you look this way for a picture, please?
快点 把他弄进里面
Come on, get him inside!
你真的是哥伦比亚人吗？
Are you really a Colombian?
你是否受到公平的待遇？
Have you been fairly treated?
请再拍一张照片！
One more picture, please!
你和南美洲任何实验室有关吗？
Are you connected with any laboratories in South America?
你为何要去巴哈马？
Why did you go to the Bahamas?
现在不准再发问了
No more questions.
你会要辩护吗？桑契斯先生
Do you expect to be vindicated, Mr. Sanchez?
等一下
Wait a minute!
好了 走吧
ED: Okay, let's go.
出发
Yeah, we're moving out.
抱歉 借几分钟
Will you excuse me, Liala? Just a minute.
- 我有个惊喜给你 - 真的？噢！
- I have a surprise for you. - Oh, really.
到这边来看看
Yes, I do. It's right over here.
那是什么？
What's that?
「詹姆斯！永远爱你 德拉与菲力克赠」
James. Love always, Della and Felix.
我们爱你
We love you.
谢了
Thanks.
快点！
Come on!
你抓住他了吗？
Did you get him?
坚持住
Hang on.
我看不见他了
I can't see him.
这里有多深？
How deep is it there?
还有多少人在里面
How many were inside?
詹姆斯！
Oh, James!
我有件东西要给你
I wanted you to have something.
你知道那传统
You know the tradition?
下一个接到这个的 表示要
The next one who catches this is the next one who…
不要
No.
谢了 德拉
No. Thanks, Della.
我该走了
It's time I left.
詹姆斯
Oh, James.
我说错什么吗？
Did I say something wrong?
他曾结过婚 但是很久之前的事了
He was married once, but it was a long time ago.
菲力克 你的腰断掉了 对我没好处
Felix, you're no good to me with a wrecked back.
让她走 你们要的是我
Let her go. I'm the one you want.
嗨 准备走了吗？
Hey! Ready to go?
潜水艇电池充电过了
We got the batteries recharged on the sub.
以极速十二里
It'll take you to the 12-mile limit.
开往古巴 你可以在那吃早餐
Fast boat to Cuba, you'll be there for breakfast.
放轻松 我们等达瑞欧
Relax. We'll wait for Dario.
你疯了吗？
Look, are you crazy?
大家都在找你
You got everybody looking for you.
基佛呢？
What about Killifer?
那条子纯粹是个疯子
Having a cop here is nuts!
我要送他「上路」
I want to deep-six him.
我和那家伙谈好了 我不能食言
I made a deal with this guy, and I'm going to keep my word.
我不喜欢他 他可以指证我
I don't like it. He can finger me.
我在这公司上投下一笔财富
I spent a fortune on this cover.
你最好了解一些事
Something you'd better understand, amigo,
忠诚比金钱对我来的重要
loyalty is more important to me than money.
现在去叫那条子
Now, get the cop.
基佛
Killifer.
这是两百万 全都是二十元面额
There's $2 million, all in twenties.
很重 但很难追查
It's very heavy, but difficult to trace.
聪明
Smart.
明天预备好
Be ready for tomorrow.
我会派人来接你
I have someone to pick you up.
- 欧培呢？- 在船上
- Where's Lupe? - On the boat.
把她留在那直到 我派人来接她
Keep her there until I send for her.
别对我女友乱来
Hey, no fooling around with my girl.
你开玩笑？
You kidding?
在你那样对待那家伙之后？
After what you did to that guy on the islands?
你喜欢我的小情人 对不对？
You liked my little valentine, huh?
我太太在哪？
Where's my wife?
别担心 我们给了她很好的蜜月
Don't worry. We gave her a nice honeymoon.
我要你明白 这非私人恩怨
I want you to know this is nothing personal.
纯粹…
It's purely.
公事
business.
基佛！
Killifer!
抱歉 老友 但二百万是大数目
Sorry, old buddy, but two mil is a hell of a chunk of dough.
桑契斯 杀了我无济于事
Killing me won't stop anything, Sanchez!
有比死更糟的事
There are worse things than dying, hombre.
地狱见了！
See you in hell!
不
No.
今天是你余生的第一天！
Today's the first day of the rest of your life.
不！
No!
谢谢你
WOMAN: Thank you.
- 早 - 早
- Good morning. - Good morning.
谢谢你
Thank you.
麻烦 你的护照
Your passport, please?
怎么回事？
What's going on?
有个大毒枭逃脱了
Some big drug dealer just escaped.
吸烟区还是禁烟区？
Now, will that be smoking or non-smoking, Mr…
你的机票！
Your ticket!
菲立克？
Felix?
德拉？
Della!
Della?
菲立克
Felix.
你不会有事的
You'll be all right. Hang on.
小子 你到哪去了？
MAN: Hey, Leiter. Where you been?
我是邦德 快叫救护车来此
It's Bond. Get an ambulance here, quick!
嗨 鲨鱼
Hi, Sharkey.
你暂时别走
You stick around.
我还有问题问你 行吗？
I might have some more questions for you, okay?
他情况如何？
How is he?
左膝盖以下没有了
His left leg's gone below the knee.
他们也许能挽救他的手
They might be able to save his arm.
一定是链锯
You can bet it was a chain saw.
哥伦比亚人用来对付告密者
Colombians love to use them on informers.
他们在这比在奥勒冈州 卖得还多
Hell, they sell more here than in the state of Oregon.
希望我能更乐观
I wish I could be more hopeful,
但得等着瞧
but we'll have to wait and see.
链锯个屁！
Chain saw, my ass!
我认得鲨吻 我看过
I know a shark bite when I see one.
桑契斯逃了
Sanchez has vanished.
取走莱特所有档案
He's got all of Leiter's files.
谁知道里面是什么
God only knows what's in them.
找到他！
Well, find him.
他在管辖权之外
He's out of our jurisdiction.
有很多国家 愿意保护他
I mean, there's plenty of countries that will protect him.
我们甚至不能引渡
We can't even get an extradition.
还有其他方法
There are other ways.
算了吧 中校
Let it go, Commander.
你什么也不干？
You're going to do nothing?
你打算这么算了？
You're just going to forget all about it?
不 我才不会
No, I'm not gonna forget about it!
看来桑契斯通边界以北的人了
Looks like Sanchez's law operates north of the border, too.
我们去猎鲨吧
Let's go shark hunting.
这是海边最后一个地方
This is the last place in the Keys.
下面得试试迈阿密了
We'll have to try Miami next.
留在这
Stay here.
你别露面 我来应付
You stay out of sight. I'll handle this.
我们下班了 这里没人
We're closed. Ain't nobody here.
我大老远从伦敦来找你们
Look, I've come all the way from London to see you.
环球出口公司
Universal Exports.
要替动物园装运一条
We've been retained by the Regent's Park Zoo.
海洋游水动物
to arrange shipment of a Carcharodon carcharias.
什么？
A what?
大白鲨
Great white shark.
没关系 菲尔 让他进来
It's all right, Bill. Let him in.
很不幸 几年前 所有的鲨鱼全卖光了
Unfortunately, we sold all our sharks years ago.
我们现在纯粹做研究了
As you can see, we do purely research now.
是一个养活第三世界的计划
It's a project to feed the third world.
把马林鱼培养成 我们特殊
We feed maggots to our special breed.
基因鱼
of genetically engineered fish,
能繁殖更多公鱼 快速增重
use hormones to make them all male, gain weight faster.
你昔日猎鲨用的？
From your shark-hunting days?
事实上要卖
Yeah. Actually, it's for sale.
我很忙 也许改天再聊
Look, I'm kind of busy. Maybe some other time.
谢谢你 下次见
Thank you. I look forward to seeing you again.
再见 先生
Goodbye, Mr…
再见
Goodbye.
克罗斯先生叫你预备好
Mr. Krest said to be ready.
三小时后会派潜艇来接你
He'll send the sub back in three hours to pick you up.
等不下去了
Can't wait.
这让我起鸡皮疙瘩
This dump gives me the creeps.
詹姆斯
James.
在那别动！
Hold it, right there.
不介意我把手拿出来吧？
Do you mind if I get my hands out of here?
慢慢来
Yeah. Do it slowly.
别动！
Freeze!
到活门去 老兄
Over by the trapdoor, old buddy.
你就是把菲力克放在那的？
Is this where you put your old buddy Felix?
不是我
Not me.
那笔帐是算桑契斯和 克罗斯的
Chalk that one up to Sanchez and Krest.
哇
Whoa!
皮箱里有两百万美金
There's $2 million in that suitcase.
我跟你平分
I'll split it with you.
你挣的
You earned it.
你留着吧 老兄
You keep it, old buddy.
多浪费
God, what a terrible waste.
那些钱
Of money.
鲨鱼！
Hey, Sharkey!
有新浪潮的消息吗？
Any news on the Wavekrest?
是艘大型的海事研究船 船东家是米尔顿克罗斯
Yeah. She's a big marine research vessel owned by a Milton Krest.
在沙尔班收集特殊贝壳
They're collecting specimens off the Cay Sal Bank.
到那儿需要多久？
How long will it take us to get there?
约六小时
Maybe about six hours.
我拿几样东西 一小时内准备好
I have a few things to pick up. Be ready in an hour.
好
Yeah, okay.
中校 有时间吗？
Hey, Commander, you got a minute?
昨晚本地警局接获 关于那仓库的密报
Local cops got a tip about a warehouse last night.
找到五百公斤哥伦比亚纯可卡因 两具尸体
Turned up 500 keys of Colombian pure, a couple of stiffs,
及一小块 基佛的肉
and a little bitty piece of what used to be Killifer.
很好 至少有人在办这案子
Good. At least someone's on the case.
你也许是莱特好友 但我只能做这么多了
You may be a pal of Leiter's, but I can only cover up so much.
检察官吼着 问是怎么回事
The D.A. Is screaming to know what happened.
我们这里也有法律
You know, we got laws in this country, too.
有法律对抗对付莱特的人吗？
Do you have a law against what they did to Leiter?
你昏了头了
Look, you're in over your head.
在这结束了 中校
This is where it ends, Commander.
你昨晚就该到伊斯兰堡了
You were supposed to be in Istanbul last night.
莱特不幸的遭遇
I'm afraid this unfortunate Leiter business.
蒙蔽了你的判断
has clouded your judgment.
你还有工作要做
You have a job to do.
我期望你今天下午上飞机
I expect you on a plane this afternoon.
这里的事还没办完
I haven't finished here, sir.
留给美国人做
Leave it to the Americans.
他们的烂摊子 让他们自己收
It's their mess. Let them clear it up.
他们不会有什么作为
Sir, they're not going to do anything.
我欠莱特
Look, I owe it to Leiter.
他冒生命危险救过我很多次
He's put his life on the line for me many times.
省省讲感情那套垃圾！
Spare me this sentimental rubbish.
他清楚要冒什么险
He knew the risks.
还有他太太？
And his wife?
你这件报私仇的事
This private vendetta of yours could easily compromise.
能轻易使女王陛下政府受窘
Her Majesty's government.
你有任务！我希望你能
You have an assignment, and I expect you to carry it out.
客观和专业的完成
objectively and professionally.
那我辞职
Then you have my resignation, sir.
007 我们不是乡村俱乐部
We're not a country club, 007.
立刻生效！
Effective immediately,
杀人执照注销
your license to kill is revoked,
我要求你交回武器
and I require you to hand over your weapon.
现在就交
Now.
我要提醒你 你依然受官方秘密协定的约束
I need hardly remind you that you're still bound by the Official Secrets Act.
我想就是
Well, then I guess it's.
向武器再见
a farewell to arms.
别开枪！太多人了！
Don't! Too many people.
主保佑你 中校
God help you, Commander.
C区有东西
Something in sector C.
小姐 你替大家惹不少麻烦
You caused us all a lot of trouble, young lady.
你这恶棍 去睡吧
You're borracho. Go to bed.
桑契斯听说你逃跑
When Sanchez heard you ran away,
他气疯了
he went nuts.
与你无关
It's none of your business.
当你这笨女人让桑契斯被捕
It's my business when your stupid little tricks.
就和我有关了
get Sanchez arrested,
我得用我的组织 不顾一切去救他
and I gotta put my organization at risk to get him out.
缉毒局刚才突击了迈亚密湾
The DEA just raided Key West.
你让我损失不少毒品
You cost me a lot of dough.
他会给你钱
He'll give you the money.
这不是他的作风
He doesn't work that way.
你最好小心点
You better watch yourself, girlie.
我认识他很久了
I've known him a long time.
像你这样的女孩 来来去去不知多少个
I've seen a lot of girls like you come and go.
你喝醉了 出去！
You're drunk. Get out.
别再从我窗户偷看
And stop peeking through my windows.
你那么臭美干嘛？
Hey, come on, come on, what are you so stuck-up for?
他安排让你赢得选美
He fixed that phony beauty contest you won.
克罗斯先生
Hey. Mr. Krest?
什么事？
Yeah, what?
桑得诺在显像器上 发现大物体
The Sentinel's picking up something large on the monitor, sir.
我想你最好去看看
I think you'd better take a look.
简直无法相信
I don't believe this.
那是什么？
What the hell is it now?
是只鲨鱼 收回探测器
It's just a manta ray. Get the probe back in.
现在开始装货
We'll start loading now.
是的
Yes, sir.
他说你没事了
He said you're okay.
好好照顾他
Take care of him.
你要出声 就死定了
Make a sound and you're dead.
你
You.
你在这儿干嘛？
What are you doing in here?
克罗斯把他的舱给我住
Krest gave me his cabin.
他住隔壁 桑契斯在哪儿？
He's next door. Where's Sanchez?
他不在船上
He's not onboard.
不知道他在哪
I don't know where he is.
你是他女友
You're his girlfriend.
他什么都不告诉我
He doesn't tell me anything.
打开 我需要跟你谈谈
Open it. I need to talk to you.
去应门
Answer it.
等等
Just a moment.
- 你想干嘛？- 有人溜上船了
- What do you want? - Somebody slipped aboard.
你看见任何人吗？
Did you see anybody?
没有 我在睡觉 走开
No, I was sleeping. Go away.
克罗斯先生 他们回来了
Mr. Krest. They're back.
拴上你的门
Bolt your door.
谁打你？桑契斯？
Who whipped you? Sanchez?
是我的错
It was my fault.
我做错事 让他生气
I did something wrong, made him angry.
克劳 干得好
Nice work, Clive.
谢谢 猜猜看怎么回事？他叫鲨鱼
Thanks, Mr. Krest. Guess what? His name was Sharkey.
把船处理掉 我们有工作要做
Get rid of the boat. We've got work to do.
你最好找个新爱人
You'd better find yourself a new lover.
你们男人 就不知道其他方法了吗？
Don't you men know any other way?
桑契斯的方法 你好像很喜欢
It's Sanchez's way. You seem to like it.
你懂个鬼
You know nothing.
请离开
Please go.
若他们找到你 我俩都会没命！
If they find you here, we'll both be killed.
留在这里
Stay here.
她已经没用了
We got everything useful out of her.
就这样了 开出去沉了她
That's it. Take her out and sink her.
好了 克劳 下去！
Okay, Clive. Cast off!
鲨鱼向你致意
Compliments of Sharkey.
有人落水了！
Man overboard!
抓住他！别让他跑了
Get him! Don't let him get away!
怎么了？
What's wrong?
回你的舱里待着
Get back in your cabin and stay there.
克罗斯先生 那家伙一定淹死了
The guy must have drowned, Mr. Krest.
别这么有把握 找到他！
Don't be so sure. Find him!
快点！
Come on!
打开桑得诺
Launch Sentinel!
是
Yes, sir!
准备听我的命令潜水
Stand by to dive when I tell you.
一号、二号 潜水
Numbers one and two, dive!
我看到有反光
I can see something reflecting over there!
太多水花无法确定
There's too much turbulence to be sure.
新浪潮！新浪潮！
Wavekrest! Wavekrest!
克罗斯先生 装好了
Loading completed, Mr. Krest.
收回桑得诺
Bring Sentinel back in.
是
Yes, sir.
克罗斯先生
Mr. Krest!
带桑得诺上来！
Bring Sentinel up!
他在那！在那！抓住他！
There he is! There! Right there! Get him!
那里！
There!
潜水！该死！潜水！
Dive, damn it! Dive!
在那！
Right there!
那里！把他捞上来！
There! Pick him up!
所有船只回到新浪潮
All boats return to Wavekrest!
是
Aye, aye, sir.
好好看着
Here. Put her stern-in.
包维尔在吗？
Hey, do you know someone called Bouvier?
在那儿
Over there.
这真是令人意外的惊喜
Well, this is an unexpected pleasure.
莱特呢？
Where's Leiter?
医院 加护病房
Hospital, intensive care.
若你不快离开 你也会在那儿
Where you'll be if you don't get out of here fast.
桑契斯有莱特的档案
Sanchez has Leiter's files.
上面有你的名字
Your name's all over them.
见鬼了！我就知道不对劲
Hell, I knew something was wrong.
那两个家伙在酒吧待好久了
Those two have been at the bar for hours.
可能在看谁露脸来找我
Probably waiting to see who showed up to meet me.
喝杯酒吗？
Would you like anything to drink?
啤酒加莱姆 一样
Bud with a lime. Yeah, same.
马上来
Sure thing, hon.
糟了！是达瑞欧 他是个煞星
Shit! It's Dario. He's bad news.
在被踢出来之前 也是中情局约雇人员
He used to be with the Contras before they kicked him out.
正是桑契斯会派的那种人
Just the kind of guy Sanchez would send.
你有带家伙吗？
You carrying?
一开火 你就趴下待在那儿
If they start shooting, you just hit the deck and stay there.
我们在哪见过？
La senorita Bouvier.Don't I know you from somewhere?
- 没有 - 见过
- No. - Oh, yes, I do.
你以前也为我朋友开飞机
You used to fly charter planes for some friends of mine.
我有样工作给你
I got a job for you.
我们到外面私下谈
Why don't we go outside, and we talk in private.
别碰她！她和我一起的
Take your hands off her. She's with me.
没人问你
Nobody's asking you, gringo.
他跟我一起 把你的手放在桌上
He's with me. Keep your hands on the table.
来了
Here we go.
二瓶 一共三块半
Two beers. That'll be $3.50.
你朋友要喝什么吗？
Do your friends want something?
我来付！
Let me get it!
他说喝够了 改天吧！
He's had enough. Run a tab.
好
Okay.
- 你怎么来的？- 搭船 ？
- How did you get here? - By boat.
- 在哪儿？- 墙后面
- Where is it? - Back behind this wall.
谢谢
Thanks.
干得好
Touche.
去发动吧
Get it started.
走吧！
Come on!
别动
Don't move.
别紧张 防弹背心
Relax. It's a bulletproof vest.
这很棒
This Kevlar's great.
你能活着已经很幸运了
You're bloody lucky to be alive!
不是运气 是经验
It's not luck. It's experience.
再高几寸就是你的头
A few inches higher, it'd have been your head.
我刚刚救了你的命
Look, I just saved your life back there.
若非是我
If it wasn't for me,
你已被钉在墙上
your ass would've been nailed to the wall.
你救我？
You saved my life?
是的
Yes.
你挑了最苦的一行
It's a tough business you've picked, Miss Bouvier.
留给专业人士吧
Leave it to the professionals.
我当过陆军飞行员
Look, pal, I was an army pilot.
在南美最恶劣的地方飞过
I have flown to the toughest hellholes in South America,
不需要你教我如何专业！
and I will not have you lecture me about professionalism.
没油了
Out of gas.
我很久没碰到这事了
I haven't heard that one in a long time.
一定打中燃料管路
Well, they must have hit the fuel line.
我需要你帮忙
Look, I'm gonna need your help.
我要彻底毁了桑契斯的作业
I want a complete rundown on Sanchez's operation,
须要私下飞到伊斯马市去
and I'll need a flight to Isthmus City, private.
不能让人知道我走了
No one must know I've left.
你去那干嘛？
What do you want to go there for?
我能付你很多钱
I'll pay you very well.
你去追桑契斯对吗？
You're going after Sanchez, aren't you?
你愿意帮我吗？
Will you help me?
你有几个人？
How many men have you got?
只有你跟我
Just you and me.
你疯了吗？
Are you crazy?
桑契斯有整个军队保护他
Sanchez has an entire army protecting him down there.
送我进去 你就走 五万元
Just fly me in and leave. $50, 000.
不是那么简单
It's not that easy.
假飞行计划要买通当地机场
False flight plans, payoffs at Isthmus City Airport.
低于十万元我做不到
I can't do a job like that for less than 100.
六万
Sixty.
- 九万 - 七万
- Ninety. - Seventy.
- 八万 - 七万五
- Eighty. - Seventy-five.
你付燃料费？
You pay the fuel?
你负责飞机
You get the plane.
成交
Deal.
为何不等别人要求你？
Now, why don't you wait until you're asked?
你为何不要求我？
Well, why don't you ask me?
第一页有五个地方打错
There are five typing errors on the first page alone.
你是怎么回事？
What's got into you?
抱歉
Sorry, sir.
美国移民局 没有报告显示007
"U.S. Immigration has no reports of 007.
今天下午三点离开美国
"leaving the United States as of 1500 hours today."
谁授权的？
Who authorized this?
是我
I did, sir.
我以为你担心詹姆斯 他失踪了
I thought you'd be worried about James. He's gone missing.
你了解他 他会去追杀桑契斯
You know him better than that. He'll go after Sanchez.
一定要阻止他
He's got to be stopped.
我已经警告我们该驻地的人
I've already alerted our man in Isthmus.
今天下午就要那份东西
I want that out by this afternoon.
是
Yes, sir.
麻烦Q部门
Q Branch, please.
这是主卧室
This is the master bedroom.
希望你满意先生
I hope everything is satisfactory, senor.
非常好
It's adequate.
我要一箱香槟 柏林加拉第牌
I'd like a case of champagne, Bollinger R. D.
没问题先生
Certainly, senor.
先生 不介意签登记卡吧？
If I could ask you to sign the registration cards?
我的执行秘书 会料理
No. My executive secretary, Miss Kennedy, will take care of that.
甘迪小姐
Miss Kennedy…
麻烦 这里
Right here, please.
每天都要鲜花
Fresh flowers every day.
谢谢
Thank you very much.
你的钥匙 住宿愉快
Your key. Enjoy your stay.
甘迪小姐
It's Ms. Kennedy,
为何你不能当我的执行秘书？
and why can't you be my executive secretary?
边境以南 是男人的世界
We're south of the border. It's a man's world.
谢谢你 你的工作结束了
Thanks for everything. Your job's finished.
- 我要留下 - 太危险了
- I want to stay. - Too dangerous.
死的人已经够多了
Enough people have been killed already.
别跟我谈危险
Don't talk to me about danger.
除非桑契斯死 不然我永远不安全
I won't be safe until Sanchez is dead.
而且 你会需要我帮忙
Besides, you could use my help.
想做我的执行秘书
Well, if you're going to stay and be my executive secretary,
你最好打扮一下
you'd better look the part.
好好买几件像样的衣服
Here. Buy yourself some decent clothes.
桑契斯用哪间银行？我要存钱
What bank does Sanchez use? I need to make a deposit.
本市最大的 依斯提斯银行
The biggest one in town, Banco de Isthmus.
是他的银行
He owns it.
邦德先生
Senor Bond.
我来存点小钱
I've come to make a small deposit.
我确信我楼下的人 相当能干
Well, I'm sure my people downstairs are quite capable of…
请坐
Please sit down.
我们是世界上 最大的私人投资基金会
We operate the world's largest private investment fund.
我们最大的问题 就是怎么处理这钱
Our biggest problem is what to do with all the money.
每天现金结存超过一千万
We have a cash surplus of $10 million a day,
经由我们的银行
which we ship, through our bank,
汇进联邦银行
to the U.S. Federal Reserve,
建立起来的信用度
thus establishing credits.
能用在任何合法投资上
which can be used for any legitimate investment.
总有人帮助老美解决贸易赤字
See, someone has to help the gringos with their trade deficit.
为邦德先生 开存款四百九十万的收据
Make out a deposit receipt for $4, 900, 000 for senor Bond.
当然每个月会有 同金额的存款
And of course there will be additional monthly deposits in the same amount.
当然 本银行
Of course. Be assured, we at Banco de Isthmus.
对这种户口很有经验
are experienced in handling accounts of this nature.
让我进去
Let me pass, please.
- 蒙奇隆哥先生 - 什么事？
- Senor Montelongo. - Yes?
我是甘迪小姐
I'm Ms. Kennedy,
邦德先生的执行秘书
Mr. Bond's executive secretary.
我会很感激 若你在赌场那边
I'd also appreciate it if you could establish.
帮我安排一下信用额度
a line of credit for me at the casino.
二百万美元如何？
Shall we say $2 million?
没问题
No problem.
你有很好的抵押品
You have excellent collateral,
赌场也是我们董事长的
and our chairman also owns the casino.
安排很方便
Oh, a very convenient arrangement.
我们一向如此 小姐
We have always thought so, senorita.
谢谢 各位先生女士晚安 欢迎收看
Thank you. Good evening, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome.
今晚很特别
This is a very special night for us.
我要各位知道 唯有你们慷慨解囊
We want you to know that only through your very generous donations.
这里的协会才能经营下去
can the work here at the OMI continue to progress.
我们学习了这么多 但还只是皮毛而已
We've learned so much, but we've only just scratched the surface.
我们需要你的帮助
We need your help.
需要你到电话旁 打电话捐献
We need you to go to your phones right now and make a pledge.
不是为我
This is not for me.
不是为他们 是为了大家
This is not for them. It's for all of us.
你没事吧？
You okay, reinita?
很好
I'm fine.
克罗斯由船上打电话给我
Krest called me from the boat.
说他遭抢了
with a story about somebody ripping him off.
当时你在 看到什么了吗？
Did you see anything happen when you were there?
没有 法兰斯 我大都待在船舱里
No, Franz. I stayed in my cabin most of the time.
我们需要你的帮助
We need your help.
怎么？
What's the matter, baby, huh?
我受不了那玩意
You know I can't stand that thing.
我要张私人桌子 21点
I'd like a private table. Blacklack.
当然 邦德先生
Certainly, senor Bond.
这边请
Would you come this way, please?
25万美金
Quarter of a million dollars,
我要提高赌注 到每一把五千
and I'd like to raise the limit to $5, 000 a box.
打给我身后这些义工
Put these wonderful volunteers behind me to work.
达瑞欧明天会带你买东西
Dario will take you shopping tomorrow.
花钱开心
You can spend a lot of money, have fun.
亲我一下
Now, give me a little kiss.
你也要？
Want one, too?
我们能涨价
We can raise the price.
这个月每公斤二万二千元
$22, 000 per kilo this month.
我喜欢
I like that.
我是杜鲁门拉巨曼
Yeah, this is Truman-Lodge.
二万二
$22, 000.
今天的目标是
Our goal today is to raise…
每一单位二万二
$22, 000 from each of our meditation chapters.
二万二
That's $22, 000 each.
拿起你的电话 协助我们
Go to your phones. Please help us.
保佑你
Bless your hearts.
再给我五十万
Let me have half a million.
曼哈顿教堂
Listen to this. Our wonderful Manhattan chapel.
刚刚特别捐了五百元
has just made a special $500 pledge.
五百公斤 我知道他们会接受
Five hundred kilos. I knew they'd go for it.
这令我啼笑皆非
This guy cracks me up.
桑契斯先生在吗？
Is senor Sanchez there?
在
Yes, he's right here.
什么事？有个呆子
Yeah? I got a British sucker.
刚输了25万
who dropped a quarter of a million,
他要玩没有最高下注额
and he wants to play no-limit.
哪一桌？
Which one?
二号桌 玩的方法真像笨蛋
Table two. Plays like a real jerk-off.
今天搭私人飞机来的家伙
That's the guy that flew in in the private plane today,
在银行里开了户头
opened that account at the bank.
五百万美元现金
$5 million in cash.
让他玩
Let him play.
赌注加倍
Double down.
分成两门
Split.
听听这个
Listen to this.
芝加哥教堂 刚刚收到一笔一千元捐款
Our Chicago chapel has just received a $1, 000 double pledge.
他们全都接受新价钱了
They all accepted the new price.
- 桑契斯先生？- 他在这
- Senor Sanchez. - Yes, he's right here.
谢谢你 芝加哥 保佑你
Bless your hearts.
这英国人赢了25万
The British guy is a quarter-million ahead.
我要关闭赌桌吗？
Shall I close the table?
不
No.
叫露比进来
Tell Lupe to come in here.
好
Right.
你今晚运气很好
You have good luck tonight.
那些钱要分我吗？
You gonna share any of that money?
帮我叫杯中甜度的 伏特加马丁尼
Miss Kennedy, would you get me a medium-dry vodka martini?
- 为什么我 - 用摇的 不要用搅拌的
- Well, why don't you ask… - Shaken, not stirred.
切牌？
Cut?
你有职业水准
You're very professional.
我以前在这工作
Used to work here.
我会赢还是会输？
Am I going to win or lose?
输 但不多
Lose, but not much.
伏特加马丁尼？
Vodka martini, que?
用摇的 不用搅拌的
Shaken, not stirred.
看来你手气变了
Looks like your luck has changed.
这是他派你来的原因吗？
Is that why he sent you?
摸清楚你
And to find out more about you.
那我今晚最好到此为止
Perhaps I'd better quit for the night.
你应该直接出去
You should walk straight out of here,
到机场永远别再回来
go to the airport and never come back.
桑契斯在哪？
Where's Sanchez?
楼上办公室
Upstairs in his office.
待了一天
He's been there all day.
计划明晚东方人的派对
He's planning a big party for some Orientals tomorrow night.
你怎么跟他提 新浪潮的事？
And what did you tell him about the Wavekrest?
什么都没说 现在走吧
Nothing. Now go.
带我去见他
Take me to him.
你疯啦？我们会因此丧命
You loco? You'll get us both killed.
先生这边请
This way, please.
向我们捐款 五毛钱也行
PROFESSOR JOE: Send us a dollar. Send us 50 cents.
捐你能捐的
Send whatever you can send.
我们有非常特别的奖品
We've got a very special offer for you guys out there.
今晚带这你的啤酒 爆米花
with your beer and your popcorn…
请稍待 几乎要结束了
This is almost over.
这本特别的书 销售超过25万本
This particular book has sold in excess of a quarter of a million copies.
任何捐超过一百元的人
Anyone who sends in a $100 pledge or more.
将收到由我亲笔签名的书
will receive a personally autographed copy of my book,
椎体电源揭秘
The Secrets of Cone Power Revealed.
景色很好
Lovely view.
定价49点95元 免费赠送给你
It's a $49.95 value, and you get it absolutely free.
詹姆斯邦德
Bond, James Bond.
请坐
Sit, please.
我们需要你的帮助 保佑你
We need your help. Bless your hearts.
爱旅行的人
Well-traveled man.
你今晚在赌桌上手气不错
You did all right at the tables tonight.
我有感觉手气要变了
I had the feeling my luck was about to change.
聪明的赌徒 知道手气什么时候变坏
Well, it's a wise gambler who knows when his luck has run out.
为何带这个？
Why this?
在我这一行 要随时准备迎接变数
In my business, you prepare for the unexpected.
是哪一行的？
And what business is that?
我帮助人解决「麻烦」
I help people with problems.
解决麻烦的人
Problem solver?
比较像是消灭麻烦的人
More of a problem eliminator.
你来办事的？
And now you're here on business?
不 暂时失业
No. Temporarily unemployed.
也许能在此找到工作
I thought I might find work here.
这里很难取得工作许可证
Well, it's very difficult to obtain a work permit in Isthmus.
要展现别人没有的特殊技能
Well, one has to show a special talent that people here don't have.
应该不太困难
Well, that shouldn't be too difficult.
邦德先生 你胆子很大
Senor Bond, you got big cojones.
你到我地盘来 没背景 就带枪
You come here to my place, without references, carrying a piece,
在这花大把钞票
throwing around a lot of money.
你要知道一件事
But you should know something…
没人看见你进来 就不需要有人看见你出去
Nobody saw you come in, so nobody has to see you go out.
桑契斯先生 我对你这种地位的人相当有用
Senor Sanchez, I could be very useful to a man in your position.
我了解你对忠实
And I understand you have a reputation.
有非常好的奖励名声
for rewarding loyalty very well.
这我保管几天 我们会再聊聊
I'll keep this for a few days. We'll talk again.
你在伊斯马不需要枪
And you won't need a gun in Isthmus.
这里很安全
It's a very safe city.
同时 随时欢迎你到赌场来
In the meantime, I welcome you to the casino at all times.
去摸他的底
Check him out.
你发现什么？
So what did you find out?
他坐在两寸防弹玻璃之后
He's sitting up there behind two inches of armored glass.
需要大跑才能做掉他
I'd need a cannon to get to him.
你叔叔来了
Senor Bond, you'll be pleased to know your uncle has arrived.
我请他到你套房去
I put him in your suite.
谢谢 晚安 先生
Thank you. Good night, senor.
你叔叔？
Your uncle?
好个家庭聚会
Let's make this a proper family reunion.
把枪给我
Give me a gun.
待在这儿
Stay here.
真是的 007！
Really, 007.
Q！你在这干嘛？我可能杀了你！
Q! What the hell are you doing here? I might have killed you!
我在休假
Well, I'm on leave.
所以来看看你的情况
Thought I'd pop around and see how you're getting on.
- 你没事吧？- 当然没事
- You all right? - Yes, of course I'm all right.
- 怎么找到我？- 当然是钱班霓
- How'd you find me? - Well, Moneypenny, of course.
她担心死你了
She's worried sick about you!
你不该来这 Q 回家去
This is no place for you, Q. Go home.
007 别傻了
Don't be an idiot, 007.
我知道你想干嘛
I know exactly what you're up to.
你需要我的帮忙
And quite frankly, you're gonna need my help.
若不是有Q部门
Remember, if it hadn't been for Q Branch,
你早就死了
you'd have been dead long ago.
给一个渡假男人用的全套配备
Everything for a man on holiday.
炸弹闹钟
Explosive alarm clock.
保证用过的人不会醒
Guaranteed never to wake up anybody who uses it.
特制牙膏 特别清理型
Dentonite toothpaste, to be used sparingly.
最新发明的塑胶炸药
It's the latest in plastic explosive.
我用得上一些塑胶炸药
I could do with some plastic.
我以为我来收烂摊子的
I thought there might be a mess to clean up.
潘 这是Q 我叔叔
Pam, this is Q, my uncle.
叔叔 这是甘迪小姐 我表妹
Uncle, this is Miss Kennedy, my cousin.
我们一定有亲情关系
We must be related.
幸会 007 注意了
How do you do? Now, pay attention, 007.
这看来似普通摄影机 对不对？
Now, this looks like an ordinary camera, doesn't it?
用哪种底片？120？
What kind of film does it take, 120?
不 点二口径的高爆弹
No, .220, high-velocity.
这枪能识别主人 这是手掌识别机
Now, this is a signature gun, and that is an optical palm reader.
当我把这插进去 一旦输入程式
And if I plug this into the bottom like that, once I've programmed it…
只有你能用这把枪
Now, nobody can use the gun but you.
笑吧 孩子们
Smile, boys.
别用那个
Don't use the flash!
别去乱碰你不了解的东西
Stop fiddling about with things you don't understand!
可能很容易就杀死他
You might easily have killed him.
奇怪的玩艺
That's odd.
让我们早点休息
Look, let's all get some rest, shall we?
明天会很辛苦
We've got a long, hard day ahead of us tomorrow.
晚安 Q
Good night, Q.
作个美梦 邦德先生
Sweet dreams, Mr. Bond.
希望你不会打呼 Q
I hope you don't snore, Q.
你们都认识杜鲁门
You all know Truman-Lodge,
这是我安全主管 海上校
and this is my head of security, Colonel Heller.
历史性的一刻
This is an historic moment.
东西双方携手
East meets West.
世界毒枭大结合
Drug dealers of the world, unite.
额外的红利 你的工作完成了
Extra bonus. Your job's done.
带他飞离此地
Take Q and fly out of here now.
我自己设法回去
I'll make my own way back.
我想要留下来
I'd like to stay.
我最好单独行动
No. I work better alone.
在这行有很多现金
In this business, there's a lot of cash,
也有很多人手会伸出来想分杯羹
and with a lot of people with their hands out.
换句话说 贿赂
In a word, bribery.
没错
Exactly.
他说出我想说的
He took the words right out of my pocket.
所以你们付钱
So you pay.
兄弟都按月领规费
Everyone and his brother is on the payroll.
所以你买通市长 警察首长 将军
So you buy a mayor, a chief of police, a general,
总统
Presidents.
有一天你醒来 拥有了整个国家
One day you wake up, you own the whole goddamn country.
随心所欲
Then you take what you want.
银行 赌场 航空公司
Bank, a gambling casino, airline concession.
为什么？
Why?
很简单 要政客收银子比吃子弹容易
Simple. It's easier for the politicians to take silver than lead.
从智利到阿拉斯加 我们有个隐形帝国
We have an invisible empire from Chile to Alaska.
朋友 我们想做的 是让你参与
What I want to do, amigos, is to make you part of it.
我要太平洋也纳入
I want the Pacific to be our little puddle.
各位 你们面前的 是一份地理报告
What you have before you, gentlemen, is a demographic report,
根据年纪 社会与经济团体
breaking down each of your territories.
列出你们每个人的地盘
by age and socioeconomic group.
可以清楚的看出 在那个活络的市场上
Now, as you can clearly see, there is a huge potential demand,
有庞大的潜力需求
given the implementation of aggressive marketing.
就像在美国
As in the United States,
桑契斯先生 打算出让独家经营权给你们
Senor Sanchez is prepared to offer each of you exclusive franchises.
每个地盘一亿元出让
The price is $100 million per territory.
我想你们已算出来 二千万美金一公顿
I believe you'll find that works out to $20 million per metric ton, Mr. Tan.
我们保证 五年的价格和品质
We guarantee quality and price for five years.
桑契斯先生
Senor Sanchez,
从我们到这开始 就吃的很好
since arriving, we've eaten well,
听了很多好消息
heard many good stories,
但在我付钱之前 我要先看硬体
but before I pay anything, I want to see some hardware.
关先生 硬体不须你付钱
Mr. Kwang, you don't pay for hardware.
你付的是我个人的保证及保护
You pay for my personal guarantee and protection.
当然若你要投资一亿元
Surely, if you were to invest $100 million,
会想要某种再保险
you would want some reassurance.
你没有错 有何不可？
You know, you're right. Why not?
明天我带你们 去分装中心
Tomorrow, I'll take you to our main distribution center.
拿去
Here you are.
再见 谢谢你所做的一切
Goodbye, Q. Thanks for all you've done.
什么？
What?
你是个出色的作业人员
You're a hell of a field operative.
走吧 我们伦敦见
Now, go. I'll see you back in London.
不再谈生意了
No more business.
各位 尽兴吧
Gentlemen, enjoy yourselves.
嗨
Hi, there!
- 嗨！- 你好吗？
- Hi! - How are you?
关先生似乎是个麻烦
This Kwang, he seems like trouble.
为何要带他们去看工厂？
Why show them the labs?
别担心 不会曝光的
Don't worry. He won't expose the operation.
罗培兹总统阁下
His Excellency, el Presidente Lopez.
我支票的金额有误
There's been a mistake with my check.
看 只有以往金额的一半
Look at it. It's half the usual amount.
当我被捕时 你非常安静
You were very quiet when I was arrested.
记住 你只有活着才是总统
Remember, you're only President for life.
你小心点 你这杂种
Watch the birdie, you bastard.
抓住他的手
Take his arm.
还会有这只掌纹枪？
Who'd have a signature gun?
詹姆斯邦德
James Bond.
这是女王陛下政府的财产
This is the property of Her Majesty's government.
你怎么会有？
How did you get it?
滚吧
Piss off.
谁命令你杀桑契斯的？
Who ordered you to kill Sanchez?
没人 他是离职的情报员
No one. He's a rogue agent.
我奉令送他回国
I've got orders to take him back, one way or the other.
我们是香港缉毒局 你这杂种！
We're Hong Kong Narcotics, you bastard!
桑契斯要带我们 到他作业中心去
Sanchez is taking us to the heart of his operations.
我已经设计多年了
I've been setting it up for years!
只能希望你这点特技 没吓到他
I just hope that little stunt of yours hasn't scared him off.
放开我
Get me out of these bloody things.
不 中校 你是个危险人物
No, Commander. You're a loose cannon on deck.
我要直接把你送回伦敦
I'm shipping you straight back to London.
- 留下他！- 不！
- Leave him! - No!
走吧！
Come on!
别让他们活捉你
Don't let them take you alive.
他还活着
He's still alive.
是谁？谁派你来？
Who was it? Who sent you?
氰化物
Cyanide.
你好
Hey, amigo!
感觉怎么样？
How do you feel?
我会活下去的
I'll survive.
露比 劳驾
Lupe, please.
新浪潮今晚会到 克罗斯会来这
The Wavekrest is arriving tonight. Krest is coming here.
不 不 不 我一会打给你
No, no, no, I'll call you back.
自由职业杀手组
Freelance hit team.
对你有何需求？
What did they want with you?
有一个必定 在赌场认出我了
One of them must have recognized me in the casino.
他们怕我警告你 坏了他们的事
They were afraid I'd warn you, spoil their plans.
你认识他们
So you knew them?
我以前为英国政府工作
I used to work for the British government.
我们有这种人的档案
We kept dossiers on such people.
英国情报员
British agent.
我就知道
I knew it.
你有格调
You have class.
那些人想要杀我
Those men tried to kill me.
谁会做这种事？
Who would do such a thing?
你身边的人
Someone close to you.
奶精？糖？
Cream? Sugar?
不要
No.
是他们告诉你的吗？
Did they tell you this?
有内线告诉他们 显然有人通风报信
They were well-briefed, obviously by someone on the inside.
有提到名字吗？
Did they mention a name?
没有
No.
他们等今晚到的人
Only that they were expecting to be paid a great deal of cash.
付他们一大笔现金
by someone arriving in Isthmus tonight.
你在怀疑谁？
You suspect someone?
我组织里的人绝对忠诚
Everyone in my organization is 100% loyal.
那你就没有什么好担心的了
Then you have nothing to worry about.
我得见几个人
Yeah, well, I have to go meet some people.
在这休息
Why don't you rest here?
不 我得回旅馆
No. I have to go back to my hotel.
别回旅馆 钱省下来 我坚持
No. Don't go to the hotel. Save your money. I insist.
留在这里 接受我的款待
Stay here. Enjoy my hospitality.
露比 带他上去
Lupe, show him the easy way up, please.
你不会相信这家伙是谁
You are not gonna believe who this guy is.
前英国情报员
Former British agent.
你怎么知道？
How did you know that?
我什么都知道
Because I know things.
我今晚要和克罗斯在船上见
I want to meet Krest's boat tonight.
需要十二个可靠的人
We'll need a dozen reliable men.
克罗斯有问题吗？
Is there a problem with Krest?
到时候便知 带露比 她当时在场
We'll see. And bring Lupe. She was there.
在她面前 他不会说谎
He's not gonna lie in front of her.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
我受够了桑契斯的款待
I've had my fill of Sanchez's hospitality.
他要你留下来 你自找麻烦
He told you to stay. You're asking for big trouble.
听着 不需要你介入
Look, there's no need for you to get involved.
给我五分钟 然后你就尖叫
Just give me five minutes, then scream your head off.
詹姆斯 听我说
James, please, listen to me.
到处都是警卫
There's guards all over the place.
你逃不掉的
You'll never make it.
我去买东西 不会去太久
I'm going shopping. I won't be long.
请别走 不是现在
Please don't. Not now.
桑契斯先生交待的！
Senor Sanchez said.
我五年没抽烟了
I haven't had one of these in five years.
别担心 007会回来的
Don't worry. 007 always comes back.
嗨 詹姆斯
James, hi.
Q 我不是叫你走吗？
I thought I told you to leave, Q.
不知道你发生何事 我们不能走
We couldn't go without knowing what had happened to you.
收拾行李
Get your bags packed, Q.
怎么了？
What the hell is the matter with you?
只有几件事
Just a couple of things.
关先生和他的队员是英国情报员 他们死了
Kwang and his team of British agents are dead.
桑契斯还活着
Sanchez is alive.
我看见你在海的办公室
I saw you in Heller's office.
你与他们是一伙的
You're working with them. No.
- 我要听实话 - 我是在说实话
- I want the truth. - I am telling the truth.
桑契斯从游击队买四枚飞弹
Sanchez has arranged to buy four Stinger missiles from the Contras,
若检察官不罢手
and he's threatened to shoot down an American airliner.
他会打下一架美国民航机
if the DEA doesn't lay off.
这和你跟海有何关系？
What's that got to do with you and Heller?
菲力克给我一封司法部长 给海的特赦信
Felix gave me a letter at his wedding from the Attorney General.
如果他可以追回那些飞弹
granting Heller immunity if he gets the Stingers back.
他接受交易了吗？
Did he go for the deal?
是的
Yes.
你没打中桑契斯
And then you missed Sanchez,
海先生惊慌了 他说交易取消
and Heller panicked and he said the deal was off,
若他再看到我 我就死定了
and that I was dead if he ever saw me again.
这不只是你个人的复仇
There's more to this than your personal vendetta.
是一塌糊涂
It's a mess.
桑契斯加强三倍守卫
Sanchez has tripled his security.
你永远无法杀死他
You'll never get another shot at him.
我们不需如此
We don't have to.
两小时后港务局会合
Meet me at the harbor master's office in two hours.
把劳斯莱斯开到旅馆前面
Q, bring the Rolls round to the front of the hotel.
是！
Yes, sir.
詹姆斯先生
Senor Bond.
蒙奇隆哥先生 我们来提款
Senor Montelongo, I'm making a withdrawal.
导航员上来了
Pilot coming aboard, sir.
怎么了？带我去舰桥
Well? Take me to the bridge.
船长 我来接手
Gracias, Captain. I'll take over now.
你？你是港口领航员？
You? You're the harbor pilot?
不 我是他的秘书
No, I'm his secretary!
交给你了
All yours, sir… Ma'am.
你不觉得进港速度太快？
Do you think you're going in a bit too fast?
你想掌舵吗？舵交给你了
You wanna do the driving? You take the wheel.
全速前进！
Full speed astern.
怎么了？
What the hell are you doing?
撞到防波堤！
Check the forward component!
港口导航员发疯了
Harbor pilot went crazy.
若我是你 我宁愿开飞机
I'd stick to flying if I were you.
我完成了我的使命
I got the job done.
法兰斯！真是惊喜
Franz, what a surprise!
没想到你会在这
I didn't think you'd be here.
是 我喜欢出其不意
Yeah. I like surprises.
最近好像有不少麻烦
You seem to be having a lot of problems lately.
来了个发疯的领航员
Well, we had this crazy harbor pilot.
谈谈你欠我的钱吧
Let's talk about the money you owe me.
里面谈
Why don't we talk inside.
- 他有保险箱吗？- 不在上面 也许在下面
- Does he have a safe? - Not up here. Maybe below.
四处看看
Have a look around.
先弄清楚
Do I have this right?
他在飞机后面滑水 跳上去
He water-skied behind the plane, jumps on it…
他是
No, no. He was…
嗯
Well, yeah.
他把飞行员丢出来 然后飞走
He threw the pilots out and flew away.
就像只小鸟
Like a little bird.
刀子
The knife.
佩德罗
Pedro.
我会编这种故事？你一定看到什么
Would I make up a story like that? You must have seen something.
- 007在哪？- 他马上来
- Where's 007? - He's coming.
这不是我的钱 我发誓
That's not my money. I swear.
没错 是我的
That's right, amigo. It's mine.
你认为我笨？
You think I'm stupid, huh?
你想污我的钱 雇人来杀我？
You rip me off, then use my own money to pay someone to kill me?
你那么想要？拿去吧！
You want it so bad? Then take it!
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
等等 跟我谈谈 不是我的钱
Wait. Let me talk. It's not my money!
怎么
No! What the…
求你了
That hurts. Please!
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
桑契斯
Sanchez.
求你 法兰斯！
Please, Franz. No!
钱怎么办？
What about the money, patron?
洗干净
Launder it.
你们从这走！
This is where you leave.
搭飞机 迈阿密见
Take the plane. I'll see you both in Miami.
你不来吗？
Aren't you coming?
不 他们会追杀我 我自己一个人比较安全
No. They'll be after me. It'll be safer on my own.
走吧
Come on, my dear.
待会见
See you later.
那是什么？
What's that?
邦德的衣服 没问题
Bond's clothes. They're clean.
抱歉吵醒你
Sorry to wake you, hermano.
我以为你想知道 你给我的情报
I thought you'd like to know the information you gave me paid off.
我抓到设计我的人
I got the guy who set me up.
只有一个人？
Only one guy?
此话怎讲？
What do you mean?
我想
I just thought that.
没人会笨到一个人来做掉你
no one would be stupid enough to try to take you on on their own.
明天和我一起去
Listen, I want you to come with me tomorrow.
去哪？
Where are we going?
一个惊喜 你会喜欢的
It's a surprise. You're gonna like it.
詹姆斯 你回来干嘛？
James, what are you doing back here?
我不认为你在这是个好主意
I don't think your being here's a good idea, Lupe.
没关系 法兰斯和中国人在吃晚饭
It's all right. Franz is having dinner with the Chinese.
明天他带我去哪？
Do you know where he's taking me tomorrow?
一个特别的地方
He's showing them a special place.
我不知道在哪
I don't know where.
詹姆斯 别走 我怕 我们会发生什么事？
James, don't go. I'm scared. What's gonna happen to us?
别担心
Don't worry.
当一切结束时 我会确定你回到家
When this is all over, I'll make sure you get back home.
家？我花了十五年才离开那里
Home? It took me 15 years to get away from there.
我不想回去
I don't wanna go back.
我们不能一起走吗？
Can't we leave together?
跟你在一起比较安全
I'll be safe with you.
不 露比 我不觉得这样很好
No, Lupe. I don't think that would work out.
没试过 怎么知道？
How can we tell unless we try?
我认为这样会很好
I think it's gonna work out very well.
好 我来开
All right. I'll answer it.
甘迪小姐？我在赌场看过你跟詹姆斯在一起
Miss Kennedy, I saw you at the casino with James.
我们需要私下谈谈
We need to speak in private.
没关系 他是自己人
It's all right. He's with me.
詹姆斯有危险 桑契斯不是笨蛋
James is in danger. Sanchez is no fool.
他在查他 如果他们发现任何可疑
He's checking up on him. You know, if they find anything suspicious…
他应该已经安全离开了
Listen, it's all right. He's safely out of the country by now.
你不了解
You don't understand.
昨晚他跟我在一起
Last night, he stayed with me.
在桑契斯家？
At Sanchez's house?
法兰斯一小时内要带他出去
Si. Franz is taking him on a trip.
你一定要帮他
They leave in an hour. You must help him.
若他发生什么事 我不知道该怎么办
If anything happens to him, I don't know what I'll do.
我很爱詹姆斯
You know, I love James so much.
有人找你前快走
Look, you must go before you're missed.
别担心 我们会想办法
Now, don't worry. We'll think of something.
「我很爱詹姆斯」 若我帮他我就受天谴
"I love James so much." I'll be damned if I'll help him.
别对他太苛
Look, don't judge him too harshly, my dear.
他们为了达成任务
Field operatives must often use every means at their disposal.
一定要不择手段
to achieve their objectives.
胡说八道！
Bullshit.
邦德刚离开别墅 两辆车及一辆吉普
Bond's just left in convoy. Two cars and a Jeep,
北上高速公路
turning north onto the main highway.
- 收到了 - 通话完毕
- I copy that, Q. - Over and out.
你把我的飞机怎么了？
What are you doing to my plane?
仔细检查 桑契斯先生的命令
Overhaul. Senor Sanchez order it.
我必须有架飞机 哪里租得到？
I must have a plane. Where can I rent one?
没有飞机
No planes.
你带着
You brought the Stingers, manito.
现在起我要它们随时在我身边
From now on, I want them close to me.
这个地方只是掩护
We started this place strictly as a cover,
乔博士带来很多利润
but Professor Joe manages to turn a tidy profit.
欢迎光临 这边请
Welcome. This way, please.
我要你们都戴上这个
I'm going to have to ask that each of you put on one of these.
为了安全起见 确定你会了解
It's for your own safety, so I'm sure you'll understand.
不能让我们最佳客户 染上毒瘾
We can't have our best customers developing a drug habit.
各位 这边
This way, gentlemen.
我们的产品能在普通汽油中 完全溶解
Our product dissolves completely in ordinary gasoline,
绝对测不出来
making it absolutely undetectable.
如何还原？
How do you get it back?
成为合伙人后 再告诉你秘密
Hey, you want us to tell you all our secrets before we're partners?
带他们去实验室
Take them to the lab.
各位 这边
This way, gentlemen.
这位新人是谁？
Who's the new guy?
有用的人
Somebody I thought could be useful.
需要效劳吗？
Can I help you?
我要给乔教授一个惊喜
I have a special surprise for Professor Joe.
抱歉 本周不接受访客
Sorry. No visitors this week.
我大老远来
I came all the way from Wichita Falls.
- 对不起 - 家乡的人一起捐的
- I'm sorry. - The folks back home took up a collection.
若乔教授不亲自收下 他们会很失望的
They'd be so disappointed if Professor Joe didn't accept it personally.
各位 可以卸下口罩
You may remove your masks now, gentlemen.
成交了吗？
So, do we have a deal?
各位 条件是
The terms, gentlemen,
一亿元无记名债卷
were $100 million in negotiable bearer bonds from each of you.
欢迎
Welcome.
乔教授 真的是你！
Professor Joe. It's really you!
太好了
It's magnificent.
全是一块块石块堆砌成的 重造它以前的光辉
Rebuilt stone for stone and restored to all of its original glory.
这是给我的吗？
Is this for me?
是的 我几乎忘了 我太沉醉了
Yes, I almost forgot. I got so flustered…
你想过来这念书吗？
Tell me, child, have you ever thought of studying here?
可能吗？
Would that be possible?
来吧 我们看看你合不合适
Come along. Let's see if you have the aptitude.
敬各位
To a long association.
过程如何？
What's the process?
很简单
It's very simple.
18%的可卡因 与普通汽油混合
An 18% mixture of cocaine and ordinary gasoline.
保持安静
Just keep quiet.
我们已经把你第一批货 装好在四辆油罐车上
We already have your first shipment being loaded into the four tanker trucks.
欢迎光临
Welcome, my dear.
请进
Please join me.
喔
Wow.
这是我远离尘土的神圣净宝
This is my humble sanctuary away from the cares of the world.
你个人的沉思教堂
Your own private meditation chamber.
用庙里圣石所建
Built from the sacred rocks of the original temple.
修建了隔音 所以没有东西打扰我沉思
I did have it soundproofed, so nothing will disturb our meditation.
我给你带来另一个惊喜
I brought you another surprise.
我喜欢惊喜 在哪儿？
I love surprises. Where is it?
真的没必要
Look, this really isn't necessary.
钥匙给我
Give me the keys.
保佑你
Bless your heart.
每月会由油轮运送
Your monthly delivery will be by ocean-going tanker.
我们会请化学技术主任 过去协助你还原过程
We'll send our chief chemist along to supervise the reconversion process.
把汽油留着当红利
You'll keep the gas as a bonus.
万一海关有问题 没有证据
And if there's a problem with customs, no evidence.
快！
Come on, hurry!
我认识他！他是告密者！
I know him. He's an informer.
你令我失望
You disappoint me.
你替谁工作？告诉我！
Who are you working for, huh? Tell me.
你不说？
You don't wanna talk?
我能弄走油罐车 但控制不了火势！
I can get the trucks out, but I don't think I can control the fire.
别管火了 车开走 开走油罐车！
Forget the fire. Get some cars.We're gonna take the tankers with us.
等等 这里花了三千二百万盖成的
Wait a minute. This setup cost us $32 million.
我们要想办法救
We have to try and save it.
我才不在乎
I don't give a shit about the setup.
皮箱里有五亿
We've got $500 million in the case and.
二十顿可卡因
20 tons of Colombian pure in the tankers.
帮海先生！
Now go help Heller.
但跟东方人谈好生意 也收了他们的钱
But we have a deal with the Orientals. We've got their money.
去帮海先生！
I said go help Heller.
要好过还是难过？
Now, do you wanna make this hard or easy?
把他放到输送带上
Put him in the conveyor.
当到你脚踝时
When you're up to your ankles,
你就会招了
you're gonna beg to tell me everything.
到膝盖时 你会感激我杀了你
When you're up to your knees, you'll kiss my ass to kill you.
我不是你的问题
I'm the least of your problems, Sanchez.
若你不相信克罗斯 你能相信谁？
If you couldn't trust Krest, who can you trust?
谁拿走你五亿员？
Who's got your $500 million?
杜鲁门？
Truman-Lodge?
飞弹呢？
What about the Stingers?
对飞弹你知道多少？
What do you know about Stingers?
我们得走了 这里随时会爆炸
We gotta go, patron. This place'll blow up any second.
海先生呢？
Where's Heller?
我不知道
I don't know.
这是你最后一次 见海先生和飞弹
That's the last you'll see of Heller and your Stingers.
谢谢你的忠告
Thanks for the advice.
开我的车到顶层见 跟我来
Have my car meet me up at the top. Braun, come with me.
你死定了
You're dead.
你正好说了我要说的
You took the words right out of my mouth.
桑契斯！
Sanchez!
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
关掉机器
Switch the bloody machine off.
我要确定这些东西会很安全
Hey. I was making sure these were secure.
好主意 拿上我的车
It's a good idea. Take them up to my car.
好
Of course.
老天 是海先生
Oh, God. It's Heller.
看来他走到死胡同了
Yeah. Looks like he came to a dead end.
快走！
Come on.
快点 快点 跟上我
Come on! Come on! Follow me!
你 跟我来
You. Come with me.
快
Come on.
意外吧！
Surprise!
保佑你！
Bless your heart!
佩雷兹
Perez.
邦德跑了
Bond has escaped.
在魔鬼关口等我
Meet me at Paso del Diablo.
别担心 只是钱而已
Don't worry. It's only money.
好了
Okay, que pase.
不！
Oh, no.
狗屎！
Shit!
太聪明了！
Brilliant.
法兰斯 漂亮！
Well done, Franz.
又有八千万美金可以抵税
Another $80 million write-off.
是缩短固定支出的时间
I guess it's time to start cutting overhead.
妈的
Dame el Stinger!
詹姆斯！
James!
你本来可以拥有一切
You could have had everything.
你不想知道原因吗？
Don't you want to know why?
你等什么？上车
What are you waiting for? Get in.
是
Yes, sir.
我下周就出院了 可以去钓鱼
I'll be up to see you next week. We'll do some fishing.
我到时候也出院了 M打来
Good. I'll be out by then. M called.
他想找你 他有任务给你
He tried to reach you. I think he may have a job for you.
菲力克 我得走了 我的主人刚到
Look, Felix, I have to go. My hostess has just arrived.
小心 詹姆斯
Take care, James.
你也是 再见
You, too. Goodbye.
我以为你不喜欢那个
I thought you hated that thing.
你不知道？蜥蜴是女孩的好友
Don't you know, iguanas are a girl's best friend.
敬你
Well, here's to you, my dear.
干杯
Cheers.
谢谢你 詹姆斯
Thank you for everything, James.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你可以跟我留在这里
You could stay here with me.
失陪了
Excuse me.
你和总统阁下 会是理想的一对
I think you and el Presidente will make a perfect couple.
为何不等别人要求你？
Why don't you wait until you're asked?
你为何不要求我？
So, why don't you ask me?